

PILAR PARDO CEMBRANO COACH (Certified PCC and CPCC)

pilar@empresasconalma.com Tfn: +34 616 46 79 69

PILAR PARDO CEMBRANO BIO

Pilar, coach and trainer defines herself as the "Alma Mater" of "Empresas Con Alma" (Companies with Soul). Her continued concern about the development of the organizations in order to improve efficiency, by improving the integration of professional and personal life led her to found "Empresas Con Alma" in order to provide an integrated service to companies who understand that people are key to their success and want to make it a competitive advantage. She also works as Certified Facilitator of Verus Global International Programs (www.verusglobal.com) and she is Certification Leader Program for the CTI Coaching Program (The Coaches Institute), previously she worked at Procter & Gamble for more than 13 years in diverse areas as Marketing, Logistics, Engineering and Production in several countries.

Pilar has intensified its studies as Industrial Engineering by the Polytechnic Center of Zaragoza with training in Co-Active Coaching (CPCC and PCC Certification by ICF- with more than 1200 coaching hours) and Master on Leadership with The Coaches Training Institute (CTI) in the U.S., training in Coaching Systems Relations and Organizations Center for Right Relationship, Master in NLP by the Gestalt Institute in Barcelona, training in Systemic Consultancy by STC Systemic, Training in Organizational Constellations by Bert Hellinger Institute in the Netherlands, several studies in the area of Emotional Intelligence and the beginning of a career in Psychology by the UNED (third year) and Gestalt Therapy..

As a coach and trainer, she works on organizational and cultural changes in companies, by developing new behaviors, process improvement and implementation of new skills in managements (leadership, communication, Design Thinking etc.) as well as technical (Project Management, Business Plans, Sales Techniques, etc..) and has performed over 800 hours of individual and team coaching in companies as diverse as Airbus, Telefónica (Technology), Grupo Santander, Bankinter or La Caixa (Banking sector), Hero, Capsa -Central Lechera Asturiana- and Loreal, (Consumer Goods), Sanitas, Bristol Meyers (Health sector), Airbus, Ferrovial, Gamesa, Tiberauto (Industrial and Services sector) and collaborates with ESADE Business School.

PILAR PARDO CEMBRANO CV

Professional Career

Alma Mater, de Empresas con Alama S.L.

2008 - now

I founded my own company "Empresas con Alma" in order to improve efficiency, by improving the integration of professional and personal life providing an integrated service to companies who understand that people are key to their success and want to make it a competitive advantage. My company continues working for several companies and on 2011 was selected as the only certified company for Outdoor Activities with the Business School Esade in Madrid. On 2010 I became Certified Facilitator for Pathways to Leadership Process from Verus Global Company what allowed me to work in several countries as USA, Mexico, Brazil, Argentina and Belgium. As of 2011 I collaborate with CTI (The Coaches Institute) as Certification Leader Program, serving coaching students to deepen and integrate the Co-Active model to become the best expression of themselves.

Consulting, Training and Coaching

2006 - now

Freelance Consultant, Trainer and Coach for several Consulting Companies for diverse sectors as Baking, Consumer Goods, Pharmaceuticals, Industrial and Services companies. My work with these companies goes from Management and Sales Skills Training to individual and team coaching programs. Additionally I work with ESADE Business School and the Madrid Complutense University as Marketing Project Teacher and Alumni Mentor on several Programs.

PROCTER & GAMBLE IBERIA (Madrid Head Quarters - SPAIN)

Iberia (Spain & Portugal) Drinks and Snacks Marketing Manager

2003 - 2005

On my last two years in Procter & Gamble additional to my responsibility as Team Leader, responsible for managing the business and the career development of my people in a difficult transition situation because Sunny Delight brand, which was 75% of our work load, was going to be sold, I lead the sales and transition process of the Sunny Delight brand, in Spain and Portugal, to the new owner (The Sunny Delight Company). On this process I worked with the new company, helping them with the design and development of their new organization with a clear objective: minimize the transition effect for the brand, securing current result from business and organization point of view.

Together with the assignment I was responsible of the Creativity and Project Management Trainings for Iberia.

Iberia (Spain & Portugal) Snack and Beverages Senior Brand Manager

2002-2003

Responsible of the Sunny Delight and Pringles brands for Spain and Portugal, leading a team of seven people including Junior Brand Managers, Trade Marketing, Logistic and Finances. Responsible for the brands strategy definition together with Central European Center in Geneva. This assignment included: definition and implementation of the Marketing Plans, consumer, trade and competition brand analysis, definition of the Marketing Mix, business opportunities and impact on brand results (sales and financially point of view) ensuring to be align and meet Company Business Objectives.

Sunny Delight Spain Brand Manager

2000-2002

Responsible for the definition and implementation of the marketing plans together with the Marketing Manager based on market, consumer and trade analysis. Working with the Creative Agencies the design of the communication strategy (including direct mail), and with different supplier for point of sales and promotional materials, and external relations activities. Key for me on that period was the development of the SunnyD 3x3 basketball program together with the Spanish Basketball Federation that was implemented on near 80% of the Spanish Primary Schools.

Logistic Team Leader 1999 – 2000

Responsible to implement the Logistic Chain to supply Sunny Delight for Spain and Portugal. This was a completely new logistic chain for Procter & Gamble in Iberia because the product must be kept refrigerated all the time. This project included the definition and start up of this refrigerated logistic chain starting at the production site in Mataro (Spain) to the point of sale (more than 500 delivery point directly and near 2000 indirectly), developing full structure including a new logistic operator, agreements with the trade and distribution, and the development of a 9 persons team responsible to support the daily business in a very complex distribution change able to supply the product in 24 to 48 hours to any point of our geography.

PROCTER & GAMBLE (Brussels European Technical Center – BELGIUM)

Control and Information System Project Manager

1995 - 1999

Responsible of the definition and start up of power, control and information systems projects on 15 European and North of Africa Production Plants. Developing projects and new technology applications for production process to increase production efficiency and quality. Working as Europe representation together with the USA; Latino America and Asia Pacific Technical Centers to develop the Global Control and Information System network to ensure appropriate implementation of global technology and suppliers.

At that time I developed a Control and Information Systems training program to increase the capabilities of the Engineering Department.

PROCTER & GAMBLE (Mataró Production Site – SPAIN)

Maintenance Manager 1993 - 1995

Responsible of the maintenance works at the Production Site. This implies the coordination and training of 18 people, developing corrective, preventive and predictive maintenance plans, improving production system always looking to increase efficiency and safety and developing a program to improving operator capabilities too with the objective to allow them to lead the maintenance programs.

Project Engineer 1991 – 1993

Responsible for the definition and implementation of new production capabilities, including viability studies, process design and development, installation and start up together with the Engineering companies. Taking responsibility too for the purchases (national and international ones) and cost control of the projects and developing the operation training program.

Education

Industrial Engineer by Zaragoza University (Spain)

2003-to now Studying Psychology Degree at the Spanish "Distance / Non presence" University Studying Gestalt Therapy at the "Escuela Madrileña de Gestalt"

Others: Pathways to Leadership Certified Facilitator

Organization and Relationship Coaching Training by Center for Right Relationship

Leadership Program of CTI in San Francisco, California.

Train on Gestalt Therapy by Secular Madrileña de Therapy Gestalt

Trained as a Co-Active Coach by (CTI)

Trained on Systemic Consultancy and Therapy with John McWhriter

Master on Neuro-linguistic programming (Institute Gestalt de Barcelona)

Train on Systemic work following Bert Hellinger Methodology in Spain and Holland

Trained as Coach by SCT Systemic

Language Skills: Fluent in Spanish (mother tongue) and English, comprehension level on Portuguese and Catalan.